BF F

Braden Frazer

Frontend UX Engineer, Design Technologist

ABOUT

Frontend UX engineer with 6+ years of experience and a blended skillset between creative and technical. Passionate about fusing the gap between design and code by building design systems and component libraries. Experienced with ecommerce, marketing, templated CMS sites, and SaaS.

EXPERIENCE

Thesis

Software Engineer (UX) • April 2024 - Present

Baylor Scott & White Health (Contract)

Front End Developer (Brand) • January 2024 - April 2024

- Ensured adherence to brand standards and the internal design system across BSWH public-facing websites.
- Analyzed and improved UI/UX across public websites after the migration from Sharepoint to Sitecore.

Dropps

UX Engineer • April 2022 - August 2023

- Systematized the design pattern library in code using Tailwind CSS and configured design tools.
- Ensured consistency between Figma and React components using Storybook.
- Backed design and 50+ A/B test initiatives with formal UX studies from Baymard and Nielsen Norman Group.
- Converted low-fidelity designs into production code for new website features as the lead frontend engineer.
- Implemented WCAG (accessibility) best practices including ARIA roles and color contrast.
- Led the migration from Material UI to Radix headless components to improve theming, accessibility, and enable server-side rendering.
- Pioneered efforts to move website code from Shopify's liquid engine over to React for greater interactivity.

Proton.ai

Frontend Engineer • May 2021 - March 2022

 Collaborated with designers to conduct user research and build features to fit client needs on an AI-powered SaaS sales platform for distributors.

Gannett I USA TODAY NETWORK

Web Developer • March 2018 - May 2021

Built and maintained 1,000+ templated WordPress sites.

Dallas, TX

⊘ bradenfrazer.com

& (281) 909-7514

bradenfrazer@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Texas A&M University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science • 2012 – 2017

Minored in Art and Mathematics. Graduated Cum Laude.

PROJECTS

Wonder Design System

Design System • Figma

A colorful, comic-like design system, inspired by Nintendo's hit 2023 video game 'Super Mario Wonder', and tailored to my own personal portfolio and brand.

Dropps UX Brief

UX Documentation • React, Tailwind CSS, Figma

A brief that highlights UX work I performed during my time at Dropps. It covers design system work, some components built, A/B tests ran, and other UI improvements.

Nintendle

Word Guessing Game • React, Tailwind CSS, Zustand

Nintendle is a Wordle clone with an emphasis on Nintendothemed solutions. The dictionary of solutions was curated by hand and includes a variety of Nintendo characters, themes, locations, and concepts.

Weathrr

Weather App • React, Tailwind CSS, OpenWeatherMap API

Weather conditions app built in React. The current temperature, humidity, pressure, wind speed, and conditions are pulled from OpenWeatherMap's API.

SKILLS

UI/UX

Figma	Design Syst	ems	A/B Testing	Storybook
Component Libraries		WCAG / Accessibility		

Languages & Tech

HTML	CS	SS	SC	SS	Tailwind	CSS	JavaScript
TypeScr	ipt	Re	act	RE	ST APIs	Git	

Other

Photoshop	Illustrator	Photography	Video Editing